<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beans on Keaton Wilson</title>
    <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/tags/beans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beans on Keaton Wilson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keatonwilson.github.io/tags/beans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Bean Markets with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/04/predicting-bean-markets-with-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/04/predicting-bean-markets-with-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>The gist Let’s dive a bit deeper into the bean project - this post is the first in a series that will hopefully get at the meat of the project. One of the main questions of this endeavor is: Can we build a model that does a good job of predicting future market prices?
More generally: If I know something about the price of garbanzo beans today, and some of the market characteristics, can I predict with a good degree of accuracy what the price will be 6 months from now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bean munging and Excel Wrangling</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/bean-munging-and-excel-wrangling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/bean-munging-and-excel-wrangling/</guid>
      <description>Messy Excel Files So, as I discussed last time, the first big hurdle in starting to explore the domestic dry bean market data was overcoming the terror of working with a bunch of really messy, really gnarly excel files.
The main one looks like this:Lots of problems, right? The data are in multiple sheets in a single workbook, they’re not uniform, etc. It’s an R-user’s nightmare, but the reality is that data often look like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview of the bean project</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/an-overview-of-the-bean-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/an-overview-of-the-bean-project/</guid>
      <description>Beans I’m the son of a bean broker. Both my dad and his dad worked in the dry bean industry in the US - which seems niche, but it’s really fascinating. When I originally started thinking about applying data science tools to problems outside of academia (in my case, outside of plants and insects and ecology), I immediately thought of beans. It’s something my father and I have talked about frequently, and a world I’ve always been interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction (a more involved ‘hello world’). </title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/introduction-a-more-involved-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/introduction-a-more-involved-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I’m an ecologist and data scientist working at the University of Arizona in Tucson. I’m currently a postdoctoral fellow with the National Institute of Health (NIH), but as that position is coming to a close, am on the job market looking for new projects and challenges.
Throughout my fellowship at the University of Arizona, I’ve become increasingly interested in data science, and have taken the plunge in applying some of the techniques I’ve developed a scientist to outside projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>