<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Keaton Wilson</title>
    <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Keaton Wilson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keatonwilson.github.io/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Algorithm for Tucson Housing Prices</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2019/01/machine-learning-algorithm-for-tucson-housing-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2019/01/machine-learning-algorithm-for-tucson-housing-prices/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The goal of this project has three main components: 1) to scrape a bunch of web data of house information in Tucson (prices, beds, baths, some other stuff), 2) to build a test a series of machine learning models that do a good job of accurately predicting the price a house will sell at and 3) taking this model and building a web interface that folks could use to plug in information on a house in Tucson and get an output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Bean Model and some additional analytics</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/06/updated-bean-model-and-some-additional-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/06/updated-bean-model-and-some-additional-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Updating the predictive bean model with new data The predictive model we’ve been exploring so far is based on data from the USDA Economic Research Service, whose database only goes to ~2011. This is a lot of data we’re missing from 2011 to the present - something we would want to incorporate into the model to improve accuracy. I recent corresponded with someone at USDA and was able to track down the rest of the data, so I’m excited to present an updated model, some predictions, and some additional insights we can gain from visualizing the model output in a couple of ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bean Market Predictions using Machine Learning Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/04/bean-market-predictions-using-machine-learning-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/04/bean-market-predictions-using-machine-learning-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Goals As I’ve discussed in earlier posts, the basic premise of this project was to use a nice (but messy) dataset from the USDA on domestic bean markets to explore a variety of different avenues of analysis, visualization and data exploration. One of the main goals of this project was to see if I could build some machine learning models that do a good job of predicting future prices of different classes of beans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preprocessing Bean Data (on the road to Machine Learning)</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/04/preprocessing-bean-data-on-the-road-to-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/04/preprocessing-bean-data-on-the-road-to-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>The gist Let’s dive a bit deeper into the bean project - this post is the first in a series that will hopefully get at the meat of the project. One of the main questions of this endeavor is: Can we build a model that does a good job of predicting future market prices?
More generally: If I know something about the price of garbanzo beans today, and some of the market characteristics, can I predict with a good degree of accuracy what the price will be 6 months from now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ecologist jumps into the deep, scary waters of machine learning...</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/the-ecologist-jumps-into-the-deep-scary-waters-of-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/the-ecologist-jumps-into-the-deep-scary-waters-of-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Misconceptions About two years ago, when I started thinking more deeply about the possibility of a career in data science, I made a concerted effort to figure out where my gaps in knowledge were (a phrase we often overuse in science, in my opinion - it feels a bit tired) and what my weaknesses were. I felt strong in R, felt that I had experience munging messy data, and felt strong in my statistical background, but I had virtually no experience with machine learning (ML), which seemed to be all anyone was talking about when I got on the web and started looking at data science positions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>