<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analytics on Keaton Wilson</title>
    <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/tags/analytics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analytics on Keaton Wilson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keatonwilson.github.io/tags/analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Classification Workshop: Introduction to Machine Learning in R with caret</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/09/classification-workshop-introduction-to-machine-learning-in-r-with-caret/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/09/classification-workshop-introduction-to-machine-learning-in-r-with-caret/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Machine Learning in R with caret Part 1 - What is machine learning? What are the tenets, what is the basic workflow? Discussion - two questions (5-minutes with the person sitting next to you - then we’ll come together and discuss as a group) What is machine learning?
 How is it different than statistics?  Some important things to know and think about: Prediction is usually more important than explanation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updated Bean Model and some additional analytics</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/06/updated-bean-model-and-some-additional-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/06/updated-bean-model-and-some-additional-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Updating the predictive bean model with new data The predictive model we’ve been exploring so far is based on data from the USDA Economic Research Service, whose database only goes to ~2011. This is a lot of data we’re missing from 2011 to the present - something we would want to incorporate into the model to improve accuracy. I recent corresponded with someone at USDA and was able to track down the rest of the data, so I’m excited to present an updated model, some predictions, and some additional insights we can gain from visualizing the model output in a couple of ways.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>