<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Keaton Wilson</title>
    <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Keaton Wilson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://keatonwilson.github.io/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The ecologist jumps into the deep, scary waters of machine learning...</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/the-ecologist-jumps-into-the-deep-scary-waters-of-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/the-ecologist-jumps-into-the-deep-scary-waters-of-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Misconceptions About two years ago, when I started thinking more deeply about the possibility of a career in data science, I made a concerted effort to figure out where my gaps in knowledge were (a phrase we often overuse in science, in my opinion - it feels a bit tired) and what my weaknesses were. I felt strong in R, felt that I had experience munging messy data, and felt strong in my statistical background, but I had virtually no experience with machine learning (ML), which seemed to be all anyone was talking about when I got on the web and started looking at data science positions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bean munging and Excel Wrangling</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/bean-munging-and-excel-wrangling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/bean-munging-and-excel-wrangling/</guid>
      <description>Messy Excel Files So, as I discussed last time, the first big hurdle in starting to explore the domestic dry bean market data was overcoming the terror of working with a bunch of really messy, really gnarly excel files.
The main one looks like this:Lots of problems, right? The data are in multiple sheets in a single workbook, they’re not uniform, etc. It’s an R-user’s nightmare, but the reality is that data often look like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview of the bean project</title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/an-overview-of-the-bean-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/an-overview-of-the-bean-project/</guid>
      <description>Beans I’m the son of a bean broker. Both my dad and his dad worked in the dry bean industry in the US - which seems niche, but it’s really fascinating. When I originally started thinking about applying data science tools to problems outside of academia (in my case, outside of plants and insects and ecology), I immediately thought of beans. It’s something my father and I have talked about frequently, and a world I’ve always been interested in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction (a more involved ‘hello world’). </title>
      <link>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/introduction-a-more-involved-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://keatonwilson.github.io/2018/03/introduction-a-more-involved-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I’m an ecologist and data scientist working at the University of Arizona in Tucson. I’m currently a postdoctoral fellow with the National Institute of Health (NIH), but as that position is coming to a close, am on the job market looking for new projects and challenges.
Throughout my fellowship at the University of Arizona, I’ve become increasingly interested in data science, and have taken the plunge in applying some of the techniques I’ve developed a scientist to outside projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>